人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  送小孩
翻译 猪猪
翻译 某羽
翻译 尼克白
翻译 泰斯
校对 泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 吉吉·波顿
时间轴 加森
时间轴 崽猪
时间轴 全家幸福筒
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
总监 泰斯·雪诺
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第一集
神作
Magnificent.
看上去像新铸的
Looks fresh-forged.
正是
It is.
瓦雷利亚毁灭以来
No one's made a Valyrian steel sword
没人锻出过瓦雷利亚钢剑
since the Doom of Valyria.
世上还有三名铁匠懂得如何重铸瓦雷利亚钢
There are three living smiths who know how to rework Valyrian steel.
手艺最精的在瓦兰提斯
The finest of them was in Volantis.
应我之邀来到君临
Came here to King's Landing at my invitation.
您从哪里弄来这么多瓦雷利亚钢
Where did you get this much Valyrian steel?
从一个再也用不到它的人那里
From someone who no longer had need of it.
您一直想要一柄瓦雷利亚钢族剑
You've wanted one of these in the family for a long time.
-现在有两柄了  -两柄
- And now we have two. - Two?
原剑大得荒唐
The original weapon was absurdly large.
足够重铸两柄
Plenty of steel for two swords.
谢谢您  真是一柄好剑
Well, thank you. It's glorious.
你得练习左手
You'll have to train your left hand.
优秀的剑士懂得如何运用双手
Any decent swordsman knows how to use both hands.
你回不到从前了
You'll never be as good.
没错
No.
不过只要我还是比别人都强
But as long as I'm better than everyone else,
料也无妨
I suppose it doesn't matter.
你一只手无法胜任御林铁卫
You can't serve in the Kingsguard with one hand.
哪里写着了  我能  我也会
Where's that written? I can and I will.
御林铁卫是终身誓言
The Kingsguard oath is for life.
战争已经结束  国王很安全
The war is over. The king is safe.
国王永远不安全
The king is never safe.
单是这座城里  就有多少人
How many people in this city alone
希望看他的头插上枪尖
would love to see his head on a pike?
你被俘时  有其他骑士护卫国王
Other knights protected the king while you were a prisoner.
你回家之后也当如此
They will continue to do so when you go home.
-回家  -你要回凯岩城
- Home? - You'll return to Casterly Rock
代我统治
and rule in my stead.
您才是凯岩城公爵
You are the Lord of Casterly Rock.
我是国王之手  我的位置在这里
I am the King's Hand. My place is here.
我死前不会再见到凯岩城了
I don't expect to see the Rock again before I die.
您知道人们叫我什么
You know what they call me?
弑君者  背誓者
Kingslayer. Oathbreaker.
毫无荣誉之人
Man without honor.
您现在又要我违背神圣的誓言
Now you want me to break another sacred vow.
你不用违背任何誓言
You won't be breaking anything.
免除御林铁卫职务已有先例
There is a precedent to relieve a Kingsguard of his duties.
国王将行使这项特权
The king will exercise that prerogative.
-不  -不
- No. - No?
不
No.
我想我不是在询问你
I don't believe I asked you a question.
这是我的回答
There's my answer.
如果你以为你该死的荣誉高于家族...
If you think your bloody honor comes before your family...
我的荣誉早就无可挽回
My bloody honor is beyond repair,
但我的回答依然是不  我不要凯岩城
but my answer is still no. I don't want Casterly Rock.
我不想娶妻  不要生子
I don't want a wife. I don't want children.
你想要什么
What do you want?
晚餐就很好
Supper would be nice.
四十年来我努力教导你
For 40 years I've tried to teach you.
你至今还是不懂  你永远不会懂
If you haven't learned by now, you never will.
去吧
Go.
如果当个高级护卫就是你的全部志向
If serving as a glorified bodyguard is the sum of your ambition,
那就去当你的
go serve.
我猜您想收回这柄剑
I suppose you want the sword back.
你留着罢
Keep it.
没有家族的独手汉需要有个依仗
A one-handed man with no family needs all the help he can get.
干一只山羊要几个多恩人
How many Dornishmen does it take to fuck a goat?
口下留德
Please don't.
要我说呀  酒馆才是旅人约见的上选
Seems to me the smart place to meet travelers is in a tavern.
那样吧  一方迟到了
That way, one party is late,
另一方还能屋里喝喝麦酒
the other party can drink some ale inside.
我们等的可是多恩亲王
This is the Prince of Dorne we're waiting for,
不是你的佣兵朋友
not one of your sellsword friends.
要是他来头这么大  干吗派你迎接
If he's so damned important, how come they sent you to meet him?
多恩的马泰尔与凯岩城的兰尼斯特
There's bad blood between the Martells of Dorne
夙有血仇旧怨  不睦多年
and the Lannisters of Casterly Rock. Has been for years.
万一多恩的马泰尔家
And just in case the Martells of Dorne
想要兰尼斯特血债血偿
are looking to spill some Lannister blood,
-不如送你上门是吧  -没必要冷嘲热讽
- it may as well be yours, eh? - No need for cynicism.
我刚好是个手腕圆滑的外交家
I happen to be an accomplished diplomat.
他们来了
Ah, here we are.
能看清家徽吗
Can you read the sigils?
黄球子
Yellow balls?
紫色旗面上一堆柠檬
Wild lemons on a purple field,
柠檬林的达特家族
House Dalt of Lemonwood.
爪子里抓着婴儿的秃鹰  布莱蒙家族
A vulture grasping a baby in its talons, House Blackmont.
戴金冠的头骨  王冢城的曼伍笛家族
A crowned skull, the Manwoodys of Kingsgrave.
这小子对多恩贵族可熟呢
Boy knows his Dornish Houses.
我也得搞个家徽
I need a sigil.
马泰尔家族的呢  金矛贯日
And House Martell, a red sun pierced by a spear?
没看到  大人
I don't see it, my lord.
幸会  诸位大人
Well met, my lords.
以乔佛里陛下之名欢迎诸位
His Grace King Joffrey welcomes you in his name.
我父亲大人  御前首相  也致以问候
My lord father, the King's Hand, sends his greetings as well.
我是凯岩城的提利昂·兰尼斯特  财政大臣
I am Tyrion Lannister of Casterly Rock, master of Coin.
请原谅
Forgive me.
怎没看到道朗亲王和诸位一道
I don't see Prince Doran in your company.
亲王贵体有恙  不便离开阳戟城
The prince's health forces him to remain at Sunspear.
他派胞弟奥柏伦亲王
He sends his brother Prince Oberyn
代他出席王家婚礼
to attend the royal wedding in his stead.
当然  有奥柏伦亲王这样的大英雄出席婚礼
Yes, the king will be delighted to enjoy the company of a warrior
国王陛下一定欣喜
as renowned as Prince Oberyn at his wedding feast.
是吗
Will he?
奥柏伦亲王殿下呢
And where is Prince Oberyn?
黎明前就到了
Arrived before dawn.
我们亲王不喜欢接风宴
Not a man for welcome parties, our prince.
诸位大人  就由都城守备队的好人们
Very well. My lords, these fine men from the City Watch
护送诸位去红堡下榻
will escort you to your quarters in the Red Keep.
长途旅行想必劳累了
You must be weary after such a long journey.
好圆滑的外交手腕
Some accomplished diplomacy that was.
现在去哪儿
Now where?
我们得在奥柏伦亲王伤人性命或大开杀戒之前
We must find Prince Oberyn before he kills somebody
找到他
or several somebodies.
这么大座城里找一个多恩人  你打算怎么找
How do you plan on finding a single Dornishman in a city this big?
如果你有操遍半个维斯特洛的名声
You're famous for fucking half of Westeros.
辛苦骑行两周  刚刚来到君临
You just arrived at the capital after two weeks of bad roads,
你会去哪儿
where would you go?
我八成倒头就睡  不过我是有点儿老了
I'd probably go to sleep, but I'm getting old.
瞧瞧这个
Look at this one.
她多好看
How lovely is she?
很美
Beautiful.
但是太苍白
But pale.
君临人喜欢白皮肤
They like them pale in the capital.
能显出她们不是田间粗妇
Shows they don't work the fields.
我吓到你了吗
Do I frighten you?
喜欢吗
You like?
太羞怯  羞怯让我厌倦
Timid. Timid bores me.
你很顽皮  是不是
You're a bit of mischief, aren't you?
我想她喜欢你
I think she likes you.
她眼光不错
She has good taste.
你不羞怯吧
You're not timid, are you?
不羞怯
Not timid.
你喜欢女人吗
Do you like women?
像她这样的就喜欢  大人
When they look like her, my lord.
这个就很好
This one will do nicely.
您喜欢就好  夫人
Very good, my lady.
我可不是什么夫人
Oh, I'm not a lady.
只是我们这里客气的叫法
A term of courtesy in this establishment.
在哪里都是谎言
A lie anywhere.
为何不用正确的说法
Why not use the right words?
我是个私生女
I'm a bastard.
她是个妓女  你是什么呢
She is a whore. And you're what?
拉皮条的
A procurer.
其他人还需要吗
Any of the others?
那两个姑娘可以走了
The two girls can leave.
你留下
You stay.
可是我不卖身  大人
I'm afraid I'm not an offer, my lord.
为小指头干活的人都能卖
Everyone who works for Littlefinger is an offer.
脱衣服  我们还有一阵子呢
Take off your clothes. We'll be here a while.
-大人  -我是个亲王  小子
- My lord. - I am a prince, boy.
你跟亲王睡过吗
Have you ever been with a prince?
没有过
Can't say I have.
我很贵的
I'm wildly expensive.
脱掉你的衣服
Take off your clothes.
您喜欢哪种方式
Which way do you like it?
我的方式
My way.
奥伯伦
Oberyn.
奥伯伦  别去
Oberyn, don't.
*雨水在大厅哭泣*
Yes, not the rains weep o'er his hall,
*内里却无人影*
and not a soul to hear.
你迷路了吗  朋友
You lost, friend?
很抱歉盯着你们看
Forgive me for staring.
在我的家乡很少见到兰尼斯特家的人
I don't see many Lannisters where I'm from.
在君临也很少见到多恩人
I don't see many Dornishmen in the capital.
我们不喜欢这里的臭气
We don't like the smell.
-跟我走吧  爱人  -天哪  你看她
- Come with me, lover. - Gods, look at this one.
先生们  请跟我来  我给你们准备单间
Sirs, if you follow me, I'll arrange for a private room.
你怎么把这么正的女人给多恩人浪费
Why are you wasting a woman like this on a Dornishman?
给他牵头剃毛的山羊再来瓶橄榄油就行了
Bring him a shaved goat and a bottle of olive oil.
你们知道为什么全世界都恨兰尼斯特吗
Do you know why all the world hates a Lannister?
你们自以为有金子有雄狮
You think your gold and your lions
还有金狮子  就高人一等了
and your gold lions make you better than everyone.
我能说个秘密吗
May I tell you a secret?
你可不是金狮子
You're not a golden lion.
只是一个拔剑太慢的
You're just a pink little man
粉面小鬼头而已
who is far too slow on the draw.
长剑可不适合近战
Longsword is a bad option in close quarters.
我一拔刀  你的朋友就会流血
When I pull my blade, your friend starts bleeding.
手腕血管密布  怕是要流很多
Quite a lot, I'm afraid. So many veins in the wrist.
如果你即刻带他就医  那还有救
He'll live if you get him help straightaway.
那么  做决定吧
So, decisions.
奥伯伦亲王  请原谅我不请自来
Prince Oberyn, forgive the intrusion.
我们听说您可能遇上...
We heard there might be...
麻烦
...trouble.
抱歉了  爱人
Apologies, my love.
我特此欢迎您来到君临
I'm here to welcome you to the capital.
这是艾拉莉亚·沙德  我的情妇
Ellaria Sand, my paramour.
这位是国王的亲舅舅小恶魔
The king's own Uncle Imp.
提利昂  泰温·兰尼斯特之子
Tyrion, son of Tywin Lannister.
如果需要我为您做点什么...
If there's anything I can do to make your stay--
你是谁  他雇的杀手吗
What are you? His hired killer?
以前是  现在我是骑士
It started that way, aye. Now I'm a knight.
你怎么当上骑士的
How did that come to pass?
可能因为我杀对了人吧
Killed the right people, I suppose.
我们还需要几个姑娘  你们要姑娘吧
We'll need a few more girls. Girls, yes?
你不来玩吗
You don't partake?
我以前玩  但现在我结婚了
Oh, I partook. Now I'm married.
奥伯伦亲王  我能和您私下谈谈吗
Prince Oberyn, if I may, a word in private?
看来我误进了兰尼斯特的窑子
Seems I visited the Lannister brothel by mistake.
-他们什么客都接  -多恩人也不例外
- Oh, they take all kinds. - Even Dornishmen.
国王非常感激您远道而来
The king is very grateful that you traveled all
参加他的婚礼
this way for his wedding.
我们打开天窗说亮话  乔佛里受辱了
Let us speak truth here. Joffrey is insulted.
毕竟我只是次子
I am only the second son after all.
同样作为次子
Well, speaking as a fellow second son,
我已经习惯了成为家族耻辱
I have grown rather used to being the family insult.
您为何来君临  奥伯伦亲王
Why did you come to King's Landing, Prince Oberyn?
我受邀参加王室婚礼
I was invited to the royal wedding.
我们不是要说亮话吗
I thought we were speaking truth.
我上次来君临是很多年前了
The last time I was in the capital was many years ago.
那也是一场婚礼
Another wedding.
我姐姐伊莉亚
My sister Elia
嫁给雷加·坦格利安  最后的真龙传人
and Rhaegar Targaryen, the Last Dragon.
我姐姐爱他  给他生下孩子
My sister loved him. She bore his children.
给他们裹被  哄他们睡觉  喂他们吃奶
Swaddled them, rocked them, fed them at her own breast.
伊莉亚都不让乳母碰他们
Elia wouldn't let the wet nurse touch them.
而英俊高贵的雷加·坦格利安
And beautiful, noble Rhaegar Targaryen
抛下她另寻新欢
left her for another woman.
由此引发了一场战争
That started a war
而这场战争就在这里终结
and the war ended right here
在你父亲的军队占领君临之时
when your father's army took the city...
我并不在场
I wasn't actually present.
他们残忍地杀害了两个孩子
...and butchered those children.
我的外甥和外甥女
My nephew and niece.
将他们切成碎块  裹上兰尼斯特的斗篷
Carved them up and wrapped them in Lannister cloaks.
而我的姐姐  你知道他们对她做了什么吗
And my sister, you know what they did to her?
我在问你问题
I'm asking you a question.
我听过一些传闻
I've heard rumors.
我也是
So have I.
我最常听到的是魔山格雷果·克里冈
The one I keep hearing is that Gregor Clegane the Mountain
强暴了伊莉亚  又用他的巨剑
raped Elia and split her in half
把她劈成了两半
with his great sword.
我不在场  我不知道发生了什么
I wasn't there. I don't know what happened.
如果杀我姐姐的是魔山
If the Mountain killed my sister,
下令的就是你父亲
your father gave the order.
告诉你父亲我来了
Tell your father I'm here.
顺便告诉他
And tell him the Lannisters
有债必还的不止兰尼斯特
aren't the only ones who pay their debts.
它们是龙  卡丽熙
They're dragons, Khaleesi.
永远不会驯服
They can never be tamed.
即使是它们的母亲也没办法
Not even by their mother.
-巴利斯坦爵士  -陛下
- Ser Barristan. - Your Grace.
达里奥·纳哈里斯呢
Where's Daario Naharis?
灰虫子呢
Where's Grey Worm?
他们在打赌  陛下
Gambling, Your Grace.
打赌
Gambling?
弥莎  弥莎  弥莎
Mhysa. Mhysa. Mhysa...
他们这样多久了
How long have they been at it?
从午夜开始  陛下
Since midnight, Your Grace.
虫子爵士比看起来要壮
Ser Worm is stronger than he looks.
但我看到他的胳膊开始打颤了
But I can see his arms beginning to shake.
赢得这场愚蠢的比试有什么奖励
What's the prize to winning this stupid contest?
胜者有幸在去弥林的路上骑行在您身旁
The honor of riding by your side on the road to Meereen.
乔拉爵士和巴利斯坦爵士将与我同行
That honor goes to Ser Jorah and Ser Barristan
因为他们今早没有让我久等
as neither of them kept me waiting this morning.
你们俩个殿后  保护牲口
You two will ride in the rear guard and protect the livestock.
最后一个放下剑的人
The last man holding his sword
可以去找个新女王效命
can find a new queen to fight for.
你喜欢这女孩吗
一定很沮丧吧
你不是聪明人  达里奥·纳哈里斯
我宁愿没脑子
也不愿没种
您必须吃点东西
You need to eat something.
鸽子派
Pigeon pie.
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
柠檬蛋糕
Lemon cakes?
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
您最喜欢柠檬蛋糕了
You love lemon cakes.
告诉她  她需要吃东西
Tell her she needs to eat.
夫人  你的确要吃点东西了
My lady, you do need to eat.
我不需要吃
I don't need to eat.
我想和妻子独处一会儿
If I could have a moment alone with my wife.
她需要吃东西
She needs to eat.
我不能让你把自己饿死
I can't let you starve.
我发过誓要保护你
I swore to protect you.
夫人
My lady,
我是你的丈夫  让我帮助你
I am your husband. Let me help you.
你能帮我什么
How can you help me?
我不知道  但我可以试试
I don't know, but I can try.
我睁着眼睛  整夜睡不着
I lie awake all night staring at the canopy
想着他们如何惨死
thinking about how they died.
我可以弄点龙葵助你睡眠
I could get you essence of nightshade to help you sleep.
你知道他们对我哥哥做了什么吗
Do you know what they did to my brother?
他们把他的冰原狼的头缝在他的身子上
How they sewed his direwolf's head onto his body?
还有我母亲
And my mother.
听说他们割断了她的喉咙  深可见骨
They say they cut her throat to the bone
又将她的尸身丢进河里
and threw her body in the river.
你的家人遭受的是可怕的罪行
What happened to your family was a terrible crime.
我不曾结识你哥哥
I didn't know your brother.
他看起来是个好人  可惜未能相识
He seemed like a good man, but I didn't know him.
而你的母亲
Your mother, on the other hand,
我很敬重她
I admired her.
虽说她曾经想处死我
She wanted to have me executed,
但我依然敬重她
but I admired her.
她是个坚强的女人
She was a strong woman.
当需要保护孩子的时候  她是那么勇猛
And she was fierce when it came to protecting her children.
珊莎
Sansa.
你母亲一定希望你能好好地活
Your mother would want you to carry on.
你知道这绝非虚言
You know it's true.
请原谅我失陪  大人
Will you pardon me, my lord?
我想去神木林
I'd like to visit the godswood.
当然可以  我听说祈祷是有好处的
Of course. Of course. Prayer can be helpful, I hear.
我再也不祈祷了
I don't pray anymore.
我只有去那里才不会受人打扰
It's the only place I can go where people don't talk to me.
我的雄狮
My lion.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你看我像是在干什么
What does it look like I'm doing?
上来
Come here.
我说过多少次了  你不能来这儿找我
How many times have I told you? You can't visit me here.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
这是一个非常危险的地方
We have come to a dangerous place.
你忘了我吗  你知道我们多久没在一起了吗
Have you forgotten me? Do you know how long it's been?
我当然没有忘记你
Of course I haven't forgotten.
我想要你
I want you.
你不想要我吗
Don't you want me?
现在形势有些紧张
Things are a bit tense right now.
什么形势
What things?
我的国王外甥想杀我
My nephew the king wants to murder me.
我妻子恨我  因为我父亲杀了她全家
My wife hates me because my father murdered her family.
奥柏伦·马泰尔想要杀掉
Oberyn Martell wants to murder everyone
所有姓兰尼斯特的人
whose last name is Lannister.
你需要放松一下
You need to relax.
你不想放松一下吗
Don't you want to relax?
-怎么了  -我跟你说过了
- What's wrong? - I told you.
-现在不合适  -从来就没有合适的时候
- It's not a good time. - It's never a good time.
-你现在有了嫩嫩的新娘  -雪伊
- You have your child bride now. - Shae.
-你爱她吗  -爱她
- Do you love her? - Love her?
我都不了解她  她是个孩子
I barely know her. She's a child.
-她厌恶我  -你答非所问
- She despises me. - That's not an answer.
我当然不爱她了
Of course I don't love her.
你曾经想把我运走
You tried to ship me away.
把你运走
Ship you away?
给我钻石然后让我消失
Give me diamonds and make me disappear.
你到底在说什么
What in the world are you talking about?
你要是想让我走  就直说
If you want me to leave, just say it.
你说啊
Say it!
我完全不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你想让我留下来吗
You want me to stay?
真是一件艺术品
A work of art, really.
做工极其精湛
The craftsmanship is excellent.
你既然这么喜欢
You like it so much,
剁了手自个儿戴上别客气
you're welcome to chop off your own hand and take it.
真是忘恩负义  我花了好几天时间
Such an ingrate. I spent days with the goldsmith
跟金匠敲定细节
getting the details just right.
好几天
Days?
差不多大半个下午
Better part of an afternoon.
好了  感觉怎么样
There, how does that feel?
钩子会更实用
a hook would be more practical.
我认为很高雅
Elegant, I think.
谢谢你帮我处理那件事
Thank you for your help with the other matter.
-症状减轻了吗  -完全没有了
- The symptoms have abated? - Gone completely.
我欠你一份人情  科本学士
I am in your debt, Maester Qyburn.
我不是学士  太后陛下  我乐意随时效劳
Not a maester, Your Grace, but happy to help whenever I can.
古怪的小个子
Odd little man.
我越来越喜欢他了
I've grown rather fond of him.
他很有才华
He's quite talented, you know?
什么症状
What symptoms?
这你就不用管了
Symptoms that are not your concern.
你让他碰你了
You let him touch you?
你嫉妒了
You jealous?
我很惊讶
I'm surprised.
你从不让派席尔靠近你
You never let Pycelle near you.
我怎么会让那个老色鬼碰我
You think I'd let that old lecher put his hands on me?
他闻起来像死猫
He smells like a dead cat.
我还真不清楚死猫是什么味儿
I'm not sure I've ever smelled a dead cat.
跟派席尔一个味儿
Well, they smell like Pycelle.
你以前不喝这么多酒
You drink more than you used to.
-是的  -为什么
- Yes. - Why?
我想想  你在街上找奈德·史塔克打了一架
Let's see, you started a brawl in the streets with Ned Stark
之后就从君临消失了
and disappeared from the capital.
我丈夫打猎时意外惨死
My husband died in a tragic hunting accident.
你还是真是凄惨啊
It must have been traumatic for you.
我唯一的女儿被送到了多恩
My only daughter was shipped off to Dorne.
我们还熬过了一场围城战
We suffered through a siege.
短暂的围城
A rather short siege.
短归短  我当时都没指望能活下来
A rather short siege that I didn't expect to survive.
现在  我的大儿子要迎娶
And now I'm marrying my eldest son
来自高庭的恶毒小婊子
to a wicked little bitch from Highgarden
我还要嫁给她哥哥
while I'm supposed to marry her brother,
一个臭名昭著的同性恋  所以...
a renowned pillow biter. So...
父亲今天跟我断绝关系了
Father disowned me today.
那不可能  他只有你了
He can't disown you. You're all he's got.
你忘了提利昂
You're forgetting Tyrion.
你不是真的还要留任御林铁卫吧
You don't really plan on staying in the Kingsguard, do you?
留任御林铁卫意味着我能留在红堡
Staying in the Kingsguard means I live right here
跟你在一起
in the Red Keep with you.
-现在不行  -我想...
- Not now. - I want--
现在不行  那什么时候  我回来好几周了
Not now? When? I've been back for weeks.
-好像有什么变了  -一切都变了
- Something's changed. - Everything's changed.
过了这么久你才回来  丢了一只手
You come back after all this time with no apologies
连一句道歉都没有  还指望一切和从前一样
and one hand and expect everything to be the same?
你要我为什么道歉
What do you want me to apologize for?
为离开我
For leaving me.
你以为我想当俘虏吗
You think I wanted to be taken prisoner?
我不知道你想什么  你又不在这儿
Don't know what you wanted. You weren't here.
你把我一人丢下
You left me alone.
我被俘的每一天  都在计划如何逃回来
Every day I was a prisoner, I plotted my escape.
每天如此  我为了回来见你而杀人
Every day. I murdered people so I could be here with you.
-你花了太久  -我...
- You took too long. - I...
-你什么意思  -我说你花了太久
- What are you saying? - I'm saying you took too long.
-进来  -走开
- Come in. - Go away.
打扰了  太后陛下
Forgive me, Your Grace.
您说过有重要事情即刻禀报
You told me to come at once if there was anything important.
你打算一个人去杀乌鸦
You plan on killing all the crows yourself?
你打算一直坐在这儿抓蛋蛋直到凛冬降临
Do you plan on sitting here scratching your balls till winter?
我们要等曼斯的命令
We wait for Mance's orders.
你满月时分派人去了长城
You sent a man over the Wall at the full moon.
既然他现在还没回来  那就是回不来了
If he's not back yet, he's not coming back.
那你想干什么
And what is it you want?
带这么点人攻打黑城堡吗
March on Castle Black with just this lot?
你那只漂亮乌鸦说那儿驻扎有一千人
Your pretty crow said 1,000 men are nesting there.
他撒谎  以后别信他
Yeah, well, he's a liar.
以后
He is?
他不应该是死了才对吗
Shouldn't it be "he was"?
你说有三支箭射中了他
You said you put three arrows in him.
没错
I did.
我见过你在二百码开外射中兔子的眼睛
I've seen you slip a shaft through a rabbit's eye at 200 yards.
如果那小子没死  只能是你故意放过他
If that boy's still walking, it's 'cause you let him go.
瑟恩人
Thenns.
我最他妈讨厌瑟恩人
I fucking hate Thenns.
曼斯派你来的
Mance sent you?
你怎么找到我们的
How did you find us?
你们从南边来  不是北边
You came from the south, not the north.
绕了路
Took a detour.
在那边的村子里搞到了晚饭
Got some supper from a village down that way.
为什么这边的肉吃起来
Why does the meat down here taste so much better
比我们长城那边好这么多
than it does on our side of the Wall?
请自便
Help yourself.
也许是这边的东西都喂得好
Maybe everything's just better fed down here.
又胖又懒
Fat and lazy.
倒是方便了我们
Easier for us, hmm?
你不知道我们要来
You didn't see us coming?
你们的易形者死了
Lost your warg?
还有那个跟你们一起的乌鸦崽子
And that baby crow you had with you,
也不在了
lost him too?
曼斯问  我答
I'll answer to Mance.
你问  我不答
I won't answer to you.
她是你的
She yours?
谁的也不是
I'm not anybody's.
太瘦了
Too scrawny.
不像黑城堡里那些乌鸦
Not like those crows at Castle Black.
想想他们窝在贮藏食物的地方
Think of them stuck in their larders
满嘴塞的都是火腿和血肠
stuffing their faces with ham and blood sausage
还有炖肉  吃得白白胖胖
and stew, getting nice and fat
膘满肉肥
and marbled.
我知道我们的口味不一样  托蒙德
I know we've had our differences, Tormund,
但你至少在死之前
but just one time before you die,
也该尝一次乌鸦肉嘛
you really ought to try crow.
拉弓
Draw.
射
Loose.
我上次见他时
Last time I saw him,
他在临冬城的院子里
he was in the courtyard at Winterfell.
他说  "下次再见
He said, "Next time I see you,
你就一身黑衣了"
you'll be all in black."
我从小就嫉妒罗柏
I was jealous of Robb my whole life.
父亲看他的那种目光
The way my father looked at him,
我也想要
I wanted that.
他什么都比我强
He was better than me at everything--
比武  打猎
fighting and hunting
骑马
and riding
还讨女孩子喜欢
and girls.
老天  姑娘们可喜欢他了
Gods, the girls loved him.
我想恨他  但恨不起来
I wanted to hate him, but I never could.
有时我想恨你
Sometimes I want to hate you.
你什么都比我强
Well, you're better than me at everything.
除了念书
Except reading.
他们...他们准备好召见你了
They're-- they're ready for you.
他早就想吊死我  现在有机会了
He's wanted to hang me for a while. Now's his chance.
没人要绞死你  你又没有错
No one's going to hang you. You've done nothing wrong.
我错得太多了
I've done plenty wrong.
你承认你谋杀了断掌科林
So you admit you murdered Qhorin Halfhand?
那不是谋杀
I didn't murder him.
不是吗  你用剑
No? You put your sword
杀死了一位守夜人军团的弟兄
through a brother of the Night's Watch.
你说这是什么行为
What do you call that?
他想让我杀死他
He wanted me to kill him.
叛国贼的野种
A bastard son of a traitor.
真是果不其然
What would you expect?
断掌认为阻止曼斯的唯一机会
The Halfhand believed our only chance
就是我们派人打进他的军队内部
to stop Mance was to get a man inside his army.
别说得好像你很了解断掌一样
Don't talk about the Halfhand as if you knew him.
他是我的兄弟
He was my brother.
那你就该知道他愿意为保护长城不惜一切
Then you'd know he'd do anything to defend the Wall.
自由民肯定会把他活煮了
The free folk would have boiled him alive,
但由我来杀他...
but letting me kill him...
自由民  听听他说什么
The free folk? Listen to him.
他说话都像个野人了
He even talks like a wildling now.
对  我像野人一样说话  跟野人一起吃饭
Aye, I talk like a wildling. I ate with the wildlings.
跟野人一起爬上长城  我...
I climbed the Wall with the wildlings. I--
我还睡了一个野人姑娘
I laid with a wildling girl.
那你承认你违背了誓言
You admit to breaking your vows, then?
我承认
I do.
法律就是法律  这小子必须死
The law is the law. The boy must die.
要是我们把每个睡过姑娘的游骑兵都砍头
If we beheaded every ranger who lay with a girl,
长城就得靠无头弟兄来守卫了
the Wall would be manned by headless men.
偷偷溜进鼹鼠村的妓院
There's a difference between sneaking off
与跟敌人睡觉是有区别的
to the Mole's Town brothel and sleeping with the enemy.
我们坐在这儿
While we sit here
为我坏了哪条规矩争论时
debating which rules I broke,
曼斯·雷德正带领十万大军向长城开进
Mance Rayder marches on the Wall with an army of 100,000.
不可能
Impossible.
不等你把五十个野人凑在一起
You can't get 50 wildlings together
他们就开始自相残杀了
before they start killing each other.
是十万  他联合了瑟恩人
100,000. He's united the Thenns,
硬足部落  冰川部落
the Hornfoots, the ice-river clans.
还有巨人为他而战
He has giants fighting for him.
巨人
Giants?
你去过长城以外吗  爵士先生
Have you ever been beyond the Wall, ser?
我指挥过君临的都城守备队  小子
I commanded the City Watch of King's Landing, boy.
可如今你到了这儿
And now you're here.
想必是指挥得不怎么样
You must not have been very good at your job.
你好大胆子
How dare you?!
有一队野人已经攻进长城以南了
There's a band of wildlings south of the Wall already
由巨人克星托蒙德率领
led by Tormund Giantsbane.
我杀了他们的易形者和另外三人
I killed their warg and three others.
他们射了我满身箭
They shot me full of arrows.
他们奉命在曼斯从北边进攻时
Their orders are to attack Castle Black from the south
从南面攻击黑城堡
when Mance hits it from the north.
以篝火作为攻击信号
The signal for the attack will be a bonfire.
曼斯说那将是北境世所未见的大火
Mance said it would be the greatest fire the North has ever seen.
这是事实
That's the truth.
全部的事实
All the truth.
你们是要处决我  还是放我自由离开
Do you intend to execute me or am I free to go?
我们都不自由
None of us are free.
我们是守夜人的汉子
We are men of the Night's Watch.
但我们今日不取你的脑袋  琼恩·雪诺
But we won't be taking your head today, Jon Snow.
走吧
Go on.
现在我是代理总司令  伊蒙学士
I am acting commander here, Maester Aemon.
对  你是
Yes, you are.
我不相信那个野种说的话
And I don't trust the bastard.
他说的是实话
He told the truth.
每次有人说谎你都能识破吗
And you always know when a man's telling a lie?
你这神奇的能力从何而来
How did you acquire this magical power?
因为我在君临长大
I grew up in King's Landing.
不行  不行
No. No.
你是王后  不是公牛
You're a queen, not an ox.
你祖父送了我一条项链  跟这条一模一样
Your grandfather gave me a necklace
作为我第五十一个命名日的礼物
just like this one for my 51st nameday.
还有两周就要举办婚礼了  祖母
The wedding is in a fortnight, Grandmother.
您不能看到什么都说不行
You can't say no to everything.
胡说  我的小宝贝们
Nonsense. My little dears.
去找君临的宝石匠
Go and speak to the jewelers of King's Landing.
报出你们的身份  你们主子的身份
Tell them who you are, tell them who sent you.
谁给我带回的项链最好
The one who brings me the best necklace
第二好的项链就归她
will get to keep the next best.
两周后要步入大教堂的玛格丽·提利尔
The Margaery Tyrell who walks into the sept
必将有千支歌谣为她传唱
a fortnight from now will inspire 1,000 songs.
如果她戴着那样的破烂  该是多么悲哀呀
Now, how sad it will be if she's wearing rubbish like that.
也许我应该让乔佛里替我挑
Perhaps I should just let Joffrey choose it for me.
最后脖子上围一串死麻雀的脑袋
End up with a string of dead sparrow heads around my neck.
讲话要注意  即使是在这儿跟我说
You watch that. Even here, even with me.
哎哟喂
My word.
夫人  小姐
My lady. My lady.
请原谅我贸然打扰二位
Please pardon me for interrupting.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮
My name is Brienne of Tarth.
我们知道你是谁  我们都听说过你
We know who you are. We've heard all about you.
不过百闻不如一见
But hearing is one thing.
你还真叫人叹为观止
Aren't you just marvelous?
英武非凡
Absolutely singular.
我听说你把我那愣头青孙儿
I hear you knocked my grandson into the dirt
摔得嘴啃泥
like the silly little boy he is.
小姐  我知道您现在很忙
My lady, I know this is a very busy time for you,
但能准许我跟您聊几句吗
but if I could just have a moment.
你哪敢拒绝
You dare not refuse.
一个影子
A shadow?
一个有着史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的面孔的影子
A shadow with the face of Stannis Baratheon.
我向诸神发誓  是史坦尼斯干的
I swear to you by all the gods it was Stannis.
他一剑刺穿蓝礼的心脏
He plunged his sword through Renly's heart
随即消失得无影无踪
and disappeared.
总有一天  小姐  我会为国王报仇雪恨
One day, my lady, I will avenge our king.
如今乔佛里才是国王
Joffrey is our king now.
我失言了
I meant no offense.
没有的事
And you've given none.
婚礼当天所有御林铁卫都要执勤
All the Kingsguard will be on duty, of course.
柏洛斯爵士在这里
Ser Boros will be stationed here.
普列斯顿爵士在这里
Ser Preston will be stationed here
就在镇场的戏班旁边
beside the primary entertainment.
陛下
Your Grace?
听到了  一个铁卫在...
Yes, yes, one guard at the--
那什么  你继续
the thing. Go on.
马林爵士护卫玛格丽小姐和托曼
Ser Meryn will guard Lady Margaery and Tommen.
我一直负责守卫国王陛下  大人
I've always guarded the king himself, my lord.
自从您离开之后
Ever since your absence.
对此我很感激  马林爵士
And I thank you for it, Ser Meryn.
很好  我不希望出什么岔子
All very good. I don't expect any trouble.
民众爱戴国王
The people love their king.
他们知道是谁给他们饭吃
They know who keeps them fed.
我听说是玛格丽·提利尔
Margaery Tyrell, I've heard.
先经过了我的许可
By my leave.
他们知道是我拯救了城市
They know I saved the city.
是我打赢了战争
They know I won the war.
战争还没赢  史坦尼斯还活着
The war's not won. Not while Stannis lives.
我在黑水河上击败了史坦尼斯
I broke Stannis on the Blackwater.
可惜你没来帮忙  舅舅
Pity you weren't there to help, Uncle.
抱歉  陛下  我当时正忙
My apologies, Your Grace. I was rather busy.
忙着当俘虏
Busy getting captured.
这就是著名的《白典》吗
So this is the famous "Book of Brothers"?
记录了所有御林铁卫的光辉事迹
All the great deeds of all the great Kingsguard.
亚瑟·戴恩爵士  拂晓神剑
Ser Arthur Dayne. The Sword of the Morning.
率队讨伐御林兄弟会
Led the attack on the Kingswood Brotherhood.
单挑击败微笑骑士
Defeated the Smiling Knight in single combat.
"高个"邓肯爵士
Ser Duncan the Tall.
邓肯爵士的事迹写了满满四页
Four pages for Ser Duncan.
他肯定很了不起
He must have been quite a man.
人们都这么说
So they say.
詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士
Ser Jaime Lannister.
有人忘了写下你的丰功伟绩
Someone forgot to write down all your great deeds.
-没到盖棺定论的时候  -是吗
- There's still time. - Is there?
只剩一只手的四十岁骑士
For a 40-year-old knight with one hand?
你这样子怎么保护我
How can you protect me with that?
我现在改用左手了  陛下
I use my left hand now, Your Grace.
更有优势
Makes for more of a contest.
你去过弥林吗
Have you ever been to Meereen?
去过几次  陛下  和克拉兹尼主人一起
Several times, Your Grace, with Master Kraznys.
还有呢
And?
据说为了建造弥林大金字塔
They say 1,000 slaves died
上千名奴隶丧命
building the Great Pyramid of Meereen.
如今这支曾经是奴隶的军队
And now an army of former slaves
正向弥林的大门开进
is marching to her gates.
你觉得伟主会担心吗
You think the Great Masters are worried?
如果他们够聪明的话  陛下
If they're smart, Your Grace.
我不是要你骑马跟在队伍最后吗
You were told to ride at the back of the train.
是的  女王陛下
Yes, my queen.
但我有要事禀报
But I need to speak to you about something important.
是战略大事
A matter of strategy.
告退  陛下
Your Grace.
好了  什么战略大事
All right, what is this matter of strategy?
一枝黑蔷薇
A dusk rose.
你想要下马步行跟在队伍最后吗
Would you like to walk at the back of the train instead of riding?
这束是仕女蕾丝
And this one's called Lady's Lace.
你想要光脚步行吗
Would you like to walk without shoes?
您要统治这里  就必须了解这里
You have to know a land to rule it.
这里的花草  河流
Its plants, its rivers,
道路  人民
its roads, its people.
用黑蔷薇制作的花茶可缓解热病
Dusk rose tea eases fever.
弥林人都知道
Everyone in Meereen knows that.
特别是泡茶的奴隶
Especially the slaves who have to make the tea.
如果您希望他们追随您
If you want them to follow you,
就要融进他们的世界
you have to become a part of their world.
这就是战略
Strategy.
金鹰妖
Harpy's Gold.
千万别用来泡茶
No tea from this one.
美丽但是有毒
Beautiful but poisonous.
你还真是个赌徒
You are a gambler, aren't you?
告退  陛下
Your Grace.
从此处到弥林  每隔一里就有个这样的路标
There's one on every mile marker between here and Meereen.
这里离弥林还有多少里
How many miles are there between here and Meereen?
一百六十三里  陛下
163, Your Grace.
我派人先行一步  把他们埋了
I'll tell our men to ride ahead and bury them.
您不需要看到这个
You don't need to see this.
不准
You will do no such thing.
我要看清他们每一个人的脸
I will see each and every one of their faces.
埋她之前先把项圈拿掉
Remove her collar before you bury her.
她在那儿
There she is.
是的  她在那儿
Yes, there she is.
-然后呢  -你答应过
- And? - You made a promise.
把史塔克家的女孩送回母亲身边
To return the Stark girls to their mother
可母亲已经死了
who is now dead.
保证她们的安全
To keep them safe.
她父亲死后  艾莉亚·史塔克就消失了
Well, Arya Stark hasn't been seen since her father was killed.
你觉得她在哪儿
Where do you think she is?
我赌她死了
My money's on dead.
死了就绝对安全了  你说呢
There's a certain safety in death, wouldn't you say?
而珊莎·史塔克如今成了珊莎·兰尼斯特
And Sansa Stark is now Sansa Lannister.
这就有点复杂了
Bit of a complication.
再怎么复杂  你也不能违背誓言
A complication does not release you from a vow.
你要我怎么做  绑架我的弟媳吗
What do you want me to do? Kidnap my sister-in-law?
绑到哪儿去  她在哪儿能比在这里更安全
And take her where? Where would she be safer than here?
看着我的眼睛告诉我
Look me in the eye and tell me
你觉得她在君临会很安全
that you think she'll be safe in King's Landing.
你真的不是我的亲戚吗
Are you sure we're not related?
自打我回来  见到的每个兰尼斯特
Ever since I've returned, every Lannister I've seen
都要跟我过不去
has been a miserable pain in my ass.
说不定你也是个兰尼斯特
Maybe you're a Lannister, too.
你有兰尼斯特的发色  模样倒不像
You've got the hair for it if not the looks.
没事的
It's all right.
别怕  别怕
It's all right. It's all right.
-你醉了  -对
- You're drunk. - Yes.
我有充足的理由喝醉
I have good reason to be.
我从前是骑士  如今沦落成弄臣
Once I was a knight. Now I'm only a fool.
您不认识我了吗
Don't you know me?
唐托斯爵士  在国王的命名日庆典上见过
Ser Dontos. The king's nameday celebration.
抱歉  我该记得的
I'm sorry. I should have remembered.
您没必要道歉
I can't accept your apology.
我虽是弄臣  但多亏您  我保住了性命
I may be a fool, but I'm a living fool, thanks to you.
换了别人也会这么做的
Anyone would have done the same.
但只有您真的做出了行动
But only you did.
您的大恩大德  我永世难报
I can never repay you.
您救了我的命
You gave me my life.
但这个  比我的生命更重要
But this, this is worth more than my life.
这是我祖母传给母亲  母亲又传给我的遗物
It belonged to my mother and her mother before her.
霍拉德家族曾显赫一时
House Hollard was strong once.
如日中天
House on the rise.
那段辉煌岁月只留下这唯一的纪念
That's all that's left of those days,
因为出了几个我这样没出息的胖酒鬼
thanks to a few sad, fat drunks like me.
我不能接受
I can't take it.
你真好  但我不能接受
It's very, very kind of you, but I can't.
我现在一无所有
I don't have anything else left.
就剩下这个
That's all.
请您收下  戴上它
Take it. Wear it.
让我的姓氏在从世间消失之前
Let my name have one more moment in the sun
再沐浴一次阳光
before it disappears from the world.
我一定会骄傲地戴上  唐托斯爵士
I'll wear it with pride, Ser Dontos.
好
Yeah.
我什么时候能有一匹马自个儿骑
When am I going to get a horse of my own?
小淑女想要一匹小马了
The little lady wants a pony.
小淑女不想再忍受你的臭味
The little lady wants away from your stench.
马儿可不容易弄到手
Horses aren't easy to come by.
就算能弄到
Even if they were,
你以为我会让你自个儿骑吗
you think I'm gonna put you on your own horse?
眼睁睁看着我唯一的财产跑掉
Watch the only thing of value I've got in the world ride away?
你怎么会没钱
Why don't you have any money?
你走之前没从乔佛里那儿偷点东西吗
Didn't you steal anything from Joffrey before you left?
没有
No.
你脑子不大好使啊
You're not very smart, are you?
我不是贼
I'm not a thief.
你杀小孩子眼都不眨
You're fine with murdering little boys,
还鄙视偷盗
but thieving is beneath you?
做男人要有原则
A man's got to have a code.
你以为我会跑吗
You think I'm gonna escape?
我能去哪里
Where would I go?
没了你  我活不到天黑
I'd be dead by nightfall without you.
我的家人都死了  没有亲人了
My family's gone. I've got no one.
你在艾林谷还有个姨妈
You've got an aunt in the Vale.
富有的莱莎姨妈
Your rich Aunt Lysa.
等我把你卖给她后
After I sell you to her,
她没准还有足够的钱
maybe she'll have enough left over
给你买一匹念念不忘的小马
to buy you that pony you want so much.
我饿了  你也饿了
I'm hungry. You're hungry.
五匹马  五个人
Five horses, five men.
我可不想饿着肚子杀这么多人
More than I feel like killing on an empty stomach.
我认识他
I know him.
小个子  他叫波利佛
The small one. His name is Polliver.
他抓住我们  带去了赫伦堡
He captured us and took us to Harrenhal.
他杀了罗米
He killed Lommy.
罗米是什么玩意儿
What the fuck's a Lommy?
他是我朋友
He was my friend.
波利佛偷走我的剑  直插进罗米的喉咙
Polliver stole my sword and put it right through his neck.
他还带着
He's still got it.
带着什么
Got what?
我的剑  缝衣针
My sword Needle.
缝衣针  你还给剑起名字
Needle? Of course you named your sword.
很多人都给剑起名字
Lots of people name their swords.
全是娘们
Lots of cunts.
你干什么  快回来
What are you-- get back here.
那把剑是哥哥送我的
My brother gave me that sword.
-给我回来  -他杀了我朋友
- Get back here. - He killed my friend.
他吃了你朋友我也不在乎
I don't care if he ate your friend.
我们不进去
We're not going in there.
来嘛  别反抗了
Come on, give it up.
过来
Come here.
-让我摸一把  -够了
- Let's have a feel there. - Leave it.
过来
Come here.
求你了  她是个好姑娘
Please, she's a good girl.
闭嘴  给我们再添些麦酒
Shut your mouth and pour us more ale
说不定等我们玩完就不带她走了
and we may not take her with us when we're done with her.
我认识你
I know you.
你是猎狗
You're the Hound.
给我们的新朋友倒酒
Pour our new friend some ale.
你怎么往北边来了
What brings you so far north?
我还没问你呢
I could ask the same of you.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing up here?
保护王国的安全
Just keeping the king's peace.
不用了  战争结束了
No need. The war's over.
我听说了  史坦尼斯败落黑水河
So I've heard. Stannis defeated at the Blackwater.
罗柏·史塔克死在孪河城
Robb Stark killed at the Twins.
那我又能怎么样呢
And where am I for all of it?
摆脱不了你哥哥
Stuck with your brother.
-无意冒犯  -没有的事儿
- Meaning no offense. - None taken.
魔山  他挺不错的
He's good, the Mountain is.
活儿干得没人能比
Best at what he does.
不过除了拷打还是拷打  没完没了
But torture, torture, torture, torture.
一天到晚拿着锤子敲人
You spend enough time putting the hammer to people,
感觉自个儿成了造椅子的木匠
you start to feel like a carpenter making chairs.
完全没有乐趣了
Drains the fun right out of it.
没乐子怎么过日子
And what's life without a little fun?
这话不用我给你讲
But I don't need to tell you that, eh?
她就这样  我手里有过更好的
She's all right. I've had better.
要我说啊
You know what?
你应该跟我们一道
You should come with us.
这种人  通常都在哪儿藏点东西
His kind, they've always got something hidden away somewhere.
金子  银子  还有闺女
Gold, silver, more daughters.
只要你懂怎么撬开他们的嘴  就有好处拿
Always something if you know how to make them talk.
从这儿到君临  他这种货色多着呢
And there's plenty of him between here and King's Landing.
你能赚好一大笔
You could do well for yourself.
我们收获就很不错
We certainly have been.
我不去君临
I'm not going to King's Landing.
考虑一下吧  我们想干什么想去哪里
Think about it. We could do whatever we like
全凭我们高兴
wherever we go.
这是国王的颜色
These are the king's colors.
如今没人敢挡他的路
No one's standing in his way now.
也就是说没人敢挡我们的路
Which means no one's standing in ours.
去他妈的国王
Fuck the king.
我听说黑水河之战中
When I heard that Joffrey's dog had tucked tail
乔佛里的狗儿夹着尾巴跑了
and run from the Battle of the Blackwater,
我还不相信
I didn't believe it.
-可你跑到这儿了  -我是来了
- But here you are. - Here I am.
给我拿只鸡来
Bring me one of those chickens.
-你有钱买吗  -你花钱了吗
- You got money to pay for it? - You paid for it?
没有
No.
但我们是国王的人
But we're the king's men.
说啊  你有钱吗
So, you got money?
一个子儿都没有
Not a penny.
但那只鸡我要定了
I'll still take that chicken.
这么说吧
Tell you what.
我们交换
We'll trade you.
给你一只鸡  换你的一个人
One of our little chickens for one of yours.
让我们跟你的朋友干一场
Give us a go at your friend.
那边的洛厄尔最喜欢"破门而入"了
Lowell there likes them a bit broken in.
你真能讲
You're a talker.
听人嚼舌头我就口渴
Listening to talkers makes me thirsty.
肚子也饿
And hungry.
我怕是要吃两只鸡了
Think I'll take two chickens.
你好像搞不清楚状况
You don't seem to understand the situation.
我很清楚  如果你这张臭嘴
I understand that if any more words
再蹦几个字出来
come pouring out of your cunt mouth,
我就要吃光这房子里所有的鸡了
I'm gonna have to eat every fucking chicken in this room.
你这辈子都为国王卖命
You lived your life for the king.
如今打算为了几只鸡送命
You're gonna die for some chickens?
送命的不是我
Someone is.
小鬼  你的腿怎么了
Something wrong with your leg, boy?
什么  你什么意思
What? What do you mean?
能走路吗  要我背你吗
Can you walk? I've got to carry you?
什么背我
Carry me?
小剑挺不错
Fine little blade.
可以给我剔剔牙缝
Maybe I'll pick my teeth with it.